W. Landgon Kihn
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
- Correspondence, circa 1904-1959, Series 2:; (Boxes 1-5, 4.0 linear feet)
  - Chronological Correspondence, circa 1917-1959, 2.2:
    - Correspondence, 1939 April-May (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence, 1939 June-August (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence, 1939 September-December (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Correspondence, circa 1940 January-April (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Correspondence, 1940 May-December (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Correspondence, circa 1941 January-June (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Correspondence, 1941 July-December (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Correspondence, 1942 January-March (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Correspondence, 1942 April-May (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Correspondence, 1942 June-July (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Correspondence, 1942 August-December (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Correspondence, 1943 January-March (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Correspondence, 1943 April-June (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Correspondence, 1943 July-December (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Correspondence, circa 1944 January-March (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Correspondence, 1944 April-July (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Correspondence, 1944 August-December (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Correspondence, 1944 November-December (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1945 January (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1945 February-March (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1945 April-June (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1945 July-October (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 1945 November-December (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, 1946 January-May (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, 1946 June-September (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, 1946 October-December (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, circa 1947 January-March (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, 1947 April-June (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, 1947 July-October (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence, 1947 November-December (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence, circa 1948 January-February (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence, 1948 March-April (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence, 1948 May-August (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence, 1948 September-December (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence, 1949 January-April (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence, 1949 May (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Correspondence, 1949 June-July (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Correspondence, 1949 August-September (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Correspondence, 1949 October (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Correspondence, 1949 November-December (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Correspondence, 1950 January (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Correspondence, 1950 February (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Correspondence, 1950 March (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Correspondence, 1950 April (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Correspondence, 1950 May (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Correspondence, 1950 June-July (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Correspondence, 1950 August (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Correspondence, 1950 September-October (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Correspondence, 1950 November (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Correspondence, 1950 December (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Correspondence, 1951 January-February (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Correspondence, 1951 March-April (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Correspondence, 1951 May-June (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Correspondence, 1951 July-August (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Correspondence, 1951 September-October (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Correspondence, 1951 November-December (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Correspondence, 1952 January-May (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Correspondence, 1952 June-December (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Correspondence, 1953 January-February (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1953 March-December (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1954 January-June (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1954 July-December (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 1956-1959 (Box 5, Folder 6)
      Index to Series 2.2: Chronological Correspondence, circa 1917-1959
      This index provides a list of selected individuals, institutions, and organizations found in Series 2.2: Chronological Correspondence.
      Ament, Robert S.
      American Museum of Natural History, New York, N.Y.
      American Federation of Arts, Washington, D.C.
      Artzybasheff, Boris
      Bowles, Chester
      Brooklyn Museum
      Canadian Pacific Railway Company, Montreal
      Cross, Wilbur L.
      Eggers, G. W.
      Ennis, Howard
      Explorers Club, New York, N.Y.
      Great Northern Railroad Company, St. Paul, Minn.
      Grosvenor, Gilbert
      Halseth, Odd S.
      Kihn, Alfred
      Kihn, Helen
      Kihn, W. Langdon
      Kirk, Ruth
      Laubin, Reginald and Gladys
      Lecompte du Noüy, Marie (May)
      Lecompte du Noüy, Pierre
      Lummis Charles, F.
      Macmillan Company
      Museum of the American Indian
      Niven, Frederick
      Oakley, Thornton
      Paisano, Ulysses
      Schultz, Hart (Lone Wolf)
      Skinner, Constance Lindsay
      Standard, Paul
      Steele, Captain Russell V.
      Stefansson, Vilhjalmur
      Stirling, Matthew W.
      White, D. Fedotoff
      Wiggins, Guy
      Ziegler, John
- Writings and Notes, circa 1920-1990, Series 3:; (Boxes 5-6; 1.0 linear feet)
  This series includes manuscripts and typescripts of articles, poems, lectures and other writings by W. Langdon Kihn and others. More detailed description is provided at the subseries level.
  The Writings and Notes series is arranged into 2 subseries:
  3.1: Writings and Notes by Kihn, date
  3.2: Writings by Others, date
  - Writings and Notes by Kihn, circa 1920-1990, 3.1:
    Writings by Kihn include his travel diary, memoir, and typescripts, manuscripts and drafts of published and unpublished articles on amateur painters, his travels documenting various North American tribal cultures and his sojourn painting in Spain. This subseries also includes Kihn's notebooks and loose field notes from his travels, and notes on the National Geographic Indians of America series.
    Additional illustrated field notes *can be found in the Sketchbooks and Sketches series.
    Materials in this series have been arranged first by format, then alphabetically by title.
    - Travel Diary, circa 1924-1925 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Aleutian Exodus, 1942 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - The Amateur Painter, circa 1940-1950 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - American Aborigine, 1924 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - American Renaissance, circa 1950-1957 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Amerindians, circa 1920-1957 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - An Artist among the Indians, 1926 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Artist and Advertiser, circa 1925-1957 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Eastern Woodland, circa 1937-1951 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - The Gitksan on the Skeena, 1925 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - The Horse Dance, circa 1920-1957 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Indians, Generally Speaking, circa 1920-1957 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Indians of the Plains, circa 1937-1951 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Legend Concerning Pictographs on the Kootenay Lake, 1922 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Little Chief, circa 1920-1957 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - The Little Lhasa of America: The Forbidden Village, circa 1924-1957 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Memoirs (Manuscript), circa 1950s (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Memoirs (Typescript), 1990 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Narrative of North American Indians, 1941, 1954, (2 folders) (Box 5, Folder 25-26)
    - National Geographic on Indians of the Americas, probably 1951 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Northwest Indian Series Captions, probably 1947 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - The Northwest Pacific Coast, circa 1951, (2 folders) (Box 5, Folder 29-30)
    - A Palette from Spain, probably 1936 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Phantoms Ride, circa 1920-1957 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - The Sun Dance, circa 1954, (2 folders) (Box 5, Folder 33-34)
    - Sunday Painting, 1949 (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - They Couldn't Paint in a Straight Line, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Vacationing in Art, circa 1932-1957 (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - Who Said You Couldn't Paint?, 1946 (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - Untitled and Incomplete Manuscripts and Typescripts, circa 1920-1957, (5 folders) (Box 5, Folder 39-43)
    - Notebooks, circa 1940s, (2 folders) (Box 5, Folder 44-45)
    - Notes on Kihn Exhibition at the American Museum of Natural History, probably 1952 (Box 5, Folder 46)
    - Notes, circa 1920-1957, (3 folders) (Box 5, Folder 47-49)
    - Notes, circa 1920-1957, (2 folders) (Box 6, Folder 1-2)
    - Notes, 1944, 1947 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Writings by Others, circa 1920-1990, 3.2:
    This series includes typescripts of poems, lectures, and writings by Agnes Akin Atkinson, C. Marius Barbeau, Lena Becker Scott, Constance Lindsay Skinner and others.
    Folders in this series are arranged alphabetically by author. Typescripts without identifiable authors have been compiled in a folder titled "Unidentified Authors," which is located at the end of this subseries.
    - Atkinson, Agnes Akin - The Fearless One, circa 1930-1957 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Barbeau, Marius, circa 1924-1925 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Authors B-W, circa 1920-1957 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Skinner, Constance Lindsay - Jaguar of San Cristobal, 1927 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Scott, Lena Becker - Dawn Boy of the Pueblos, probably 1935, (2 folders) (Box 6, Folder 8-9)
    - Unidentified Authors, 1932 (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Printed Material, circa 1920-1957, Series 4:; (Boxes 6-8, OV 10; 2.2 linear feet)
  Items in this series document Kihn's life and work though exhibition announcements, catalogs, invitations, annual reports, course lists, book covers, publication announcements, brochures, travel related materials, ephemera, newspaper clippings, and magazines that contain articles about Kihn or examples of his work. There are also extensive examples of Kihn's work as an illustrator including proofs of his illustrations for the books Beaver, Kings, and Cabins (1933) by Constance Lindsay Skinner and Dawn Boy of the Pueblos (1935) by Laura Becker Scott, among others. Additionally there are proofs of plates, engraved after Kihn's original paintings and drawings, for the National Geographic magazines ongoing series on North American Indian life and history.
  Printed materials are arranged by format type.
  - Exhibition Announcements, Catalogs, and Invitations-Kihn, circa 1922 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Exhibition Announcements, Catalogs, and Invitations-Kihn, 1923 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Exhibition Announcements, Catalogs, and Invitations-Kihn, 1924-1927 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Exhibition Announcements, Catalogs, and Invitations-Kihn, 1927-1929 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Exhibition Announcements, Catalogs, and Invitations-Kihn, 1930-1948 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Exhibition Announcements, Catalogs, and Invitations-Kihn, 1949-1957 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Exhibition Announcements, Catalogs, and Invitations-Kihn, undated (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Exhibition Announcements, Catalogs, and Invitations-General, 1922, 1924 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Exhibition Announcements, Catalogs, and Invitations-General, circa 1925-1954 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Exhibition Press Releases, circa 1922-1956 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Ephemera, Brochures, and Publications-Annual Reports, circa 1926-1954 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Ephemera, Brochures, and Publications-Art Schools and College Course Lists, circa 1921-1956 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Ephemera, Brochures, and Publications-Book Covers and Publication Announcements, circa 1925-1957 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Ephemera, Brochures, and Publications-Buffalo, New York Trip, 1953 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Ephemera, Brochures, and Publications-Connecticut Forest and Park Association, circa 1938-1956 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Ephemera, Brochures, and Publications-Event Programs and Promotional Brochures, circa 1920-1957 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Ephemera, Brochures, and Publications-The Explorers Club, 1932-1950 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Ephemera, Brochures, and Publications-Travel, circa 1929-1957 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Ephemera, Brochures, and Publications-General, circa 1920-1957 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Illustrations for Beaver, Kings and Cabins, circa 1933 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Illustrations for The Big Canoe, circa 1933 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Illustrations for Dawn Boy, circa 1935 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Illustrations for Desert Wife, circa 1934 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Unidentified Illustrations, circa 1930s, (see also OV 10) (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Proofs of Northeastern Woodland Indians, 1937, (2 folders) (Box 7, Folder 6-7)
  - Proofs of Indians of the Southwest, circa 1938 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Plates of Indians of the Southwest, circa 1938 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Proofs of The Plains Indians, circa 1941 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Proofs of Totem Pole Indians of the Pacific Northwest, circa 1944 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Proofs of Southeastern Indians, circa 1945 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Proofs of Aborigines of the Far North, circa 1948 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Proofs of Indians of the Americas, circa 1955, (2 folders) (Box 7, Folder 14-15)
  - Proofs and Dummies for National Geographic and As in the Days of Adam, 1949, 1952 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Unidentified Proofs, circa 1950s (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Printed Reproductions of Kihn's Art (examples of commercial work), circa 1924-1957 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Newspaper Clippings Scrapbook, 1913-1923, (unbound scrapbook) (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Newspaper and Magazine Clippings, 1921-1922 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Newspaper and Magazine Clippings, 1923-1924 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Newspaper and Magazine Clippings, 1925 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Newspaper and Magazine Clippings, 1926-1928 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Newspaper and Magazine Clippings, 1929 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Newspaper and Magazine Clippings, 1930-1932 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Newspaper and Magazine Clippings, 1933 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Newspaper and Magazine Clippings, 1934-1935 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Newspaper and Magazine Clippings, 1936-1938 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Newspaper and Magazine Clippings, 1941-1947 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Newspaper and Magazine Clippings, 1948-1949 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Newspaper and Magazine Clippings, 1950-1951 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Newspaper and Magazine Clippings, 1952-1954 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Newspaper and Magazine Clippings, undated (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Newspaper and Magazine Clippings - General, 1920-1950 (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Magazines and Journals, 1907, 1921-1922 (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - Magazines and Journals, 1923 (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - Magazines and Journals, 1924 (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - Magazines and Journals, 1925, (2 folders; see also OV 10) (Box 8, Folder 1-2)
  - Magazines and Journals, 1926-1927 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Magazines and Journals, 1928 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Magazines and Journals, 1929-1932 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Magazines and Journals, 1933-1935 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Magazines and Journals, 1936 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Magazines and Journals, 1938-1939 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Magazines and Journals, 1940-1947 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Magazines and Journals, 1950 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Magazines and Journals, 1951-1952 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Oversize, Book Illustrations, circa 1930s, (See also Box 7, F5) (Box OV 10)
  - Oversize, Magazine, 1925, (See also Box 8, F1-2) (Box OV 10)
- Financial Records, 1920-1955, Series 5:; (Box 8; 0.3 linear feet)
  Found in this series are account books, invoices and receipts, including work related documents such as receipts for photographs of his work, shipping, picture framing, art supplies, travel related expenses; gallery invoices of paintings received; and payment invoices for illustrations and gallery sales. There are also receipts for household expenses.
  Financial records are arranged by format and then chronologically by year.
  - Account Book for the Guy Wiggins-W. Langdon Kihn Art School, 1949-1951 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Expense Account Books, circa 1938-1950 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Invoices and Receipts, 1920-1922 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Invoices and Receipts, 1923 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Invoices and Receipts, 1924-1925 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Invoices and Receipts, 1926 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Invoices and Receipts, 1927-1928 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Invoices and Receipts, 1929 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Invoices and Receipts, 1930 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Invoices and Receipts, 1931-1933 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Invoices and Receipts, 1934-1939 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Invoices and Receipts, 1940-1944 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Invoices and Receipts, 1945-1946 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Invoices and Receipts, 1946-1947 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Invoices and Receipts, 1949 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Invoices and Receipts, 1950-1955 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Invoices and Receipts, undated (Box 8, Folder 28)
- Sketchbooks and Sketches, circa 1922-1955, Series 6:; (Box 8-9, OV 10; 0.5 linear feet
  Items in this series include illustrated field notes, ink studies for book and magazine illustrations, studies for federal art projects such as paintings for the Nathan Hale Library in Connecticut, three sketchbooks and loose sketches from Kihn's travels observing North American Indian tribal culture and a study and finished sign for the "Langdon Kihn Art Classes." There is also a folder of work by other artists.
  Sketchbooks and sketches have been roughly grouped together by type and subject.
  - Sketchbook, circa 1940s (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Sketchbook, undated (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - "Plains Notes" Sketchbook, 1940 (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Sketches of Landscapes and Birds, undated (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - Sketches and Illustrated Field Notes on American Indians, circa 1922-1947, (3 folders; see OV 10 for oversized items) (Box 8, Folder 33-35)
  - Sketches and Studies for Nathan Hale School, Rathbun Library, etc., circa 1930s (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - Sketches of British Columbia and Southwest, circa 1935-1945 (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - Sketches (Southwest?), circa 1930s (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Sketches - General, circa 1930-1955 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Studies on Board, circa 1930-1955, (3 studies on brittle acidic board) (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - "Langdon Kihn Art Classes" Sign, circa 1932-1948, (painted proof and printed sign) (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Studies for Book Illustrations for Dawn Boy of the Puebloes, circa 1935 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Studies and Ink Drawings for Book Illustrations for Desert Wife, circa 1934 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Studies and Ink Drawings for Book Illustrations for Flat Tail, circa 1935 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Studies for Book Illustrations for Trail of the Borealis, circa 1934 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Studies and Ink Drawings for Book Illustrations for The Wolf Gang, circa 1935 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Ink Drawings for Illustrations for Story Parade and Other Projects, circa 1935-1945 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Sketches and Artworks by Others, undated (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Oversize, Sketches and Illustrated Field Notes, undated, (Oversized items from Box 8, F 33-35) (Box OV 10)
- Photographs, circa 1920-1955, Series 7:
  This series includes photographs of Kihn at work, alone, and with others; source photographs used by Kihn; and photographs of his paintings and drawings.
  Photographs have been grouped together by subject.
  - W. Langdon Kihn and Others, circa 1920-1955 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Source Photographs used by Kihn, circa 1935-1947 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Reproductions of Artworks, circa 1920-1955, (3 folders) (Box 9, Folder 14-16)